<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EA Zurich</title>
    <link>https://eazurich.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on EA Zurich</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 15:58:33 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://eazurich.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Organization</title>
      <link>https://eazurich.org/organizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 15:58:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eazurich.org/organizations/</guid>
      <description>Organizations 
80,000 Hours (80K) is an organization that offers free, one-on-one career advice to individuals seeking to use their careers to do the most good in the world. 80K also publishes general research on the social impact of careers to its website.
Against Malaria Foundation (AMF) is a non-profit that funds the distribution of long-lasting insecticidal nets (LLIN) to areas with high incidence of malaria, mostly in Africa. GiveWell has recommended AMF as a top charity several times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Altruism</title>
      <link>https://eazurich.org/effective-altruism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 15:58:29 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eazurich.org/effective-altruism/</guid>
      <description>Effective altruism is about answering one simple question: how can we use our resources to help others the most?
Rather than just doing what feels right, we use evidence and careful analysis to find the very best causes to work on.
But it&amp;rsquo;s no use answering the question unless you act on it. Effective altruism is about following through. It&amp;rsquo;s about being generous with your time and your money to do the most good you can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Terms</title>
      <link>https://eazurich.org/key-terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 15:58:20 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eazurich.org/key-terms/</guid>
      <description>Key EA Terms 
Core Ideas Effective Altruism (EA) is the name of a growing social movement and an idea – based around using careful reasoning to find the most effective possible ways of doing good in the world. An effective altruist is someone who identifies with and tries to act according to the principles of Effective Altruism.
Cost-effectiveness: The cost-effectiveness of a charitable intervention simply refers to how much good it does with a certain amount of resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Material</title>
      <link>https://eazurich.org/reading-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 15:58:15 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eazurich.org/reading-material/</guid>
      <description>Reading Material 
A lot of material has been developed on effective altruism. Here is some of it.
For a short introduction, watch Will MacAskill&amp;rsquo;s What are the most important moral problems of our time?.
You can find a list of EA reading resources here, as well as a collection of excellent articles.
The organization 80.000 hours have put together a thorough career guide on how to tackle the world&amp;rsquo;s most pressing problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://eazurich.org/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 02:15:52 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eazurich.org/contact/</guid>
      <description>This is the contact page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>https://eazurich.org/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 02:15:52 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eazurich.org/faq/</guid>
      <description>Frequently Asked Questions So what is effective altruism?    The core idea:  Effective altruism is using evidence and analysis to take actions that help others as much as possible.  The world has a lot of horrible problems but we can’t work on them all at once. Our goal is to accomplish the most good for the world with our limited time, energy, and resources.  There is a lot of agreement among people in the movement about what questions we should ask when figuring out what will help others the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://eazurich.org/_footer-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eazurich.org/_footer-center/</guid>
      <description> Useful links  effectivealtruism.org 80000 Hours GiveWell Effective Altruism Foundation Centre for Effective Altruism  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://eazurich.org/_footer-left/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eazurich.org/_footer-left/</guid>
      <description> More on EA  Intro to effective altruism Video: What are the most important moral problems of our time? 80.000 Hours career guide EA Forum  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://eazurich.org/homepage/_first_section_text/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eazurich.org/homepage/_first_section_text/</guid>
      <description>We want to help you use evidence and reason to make the world a better place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://eazurich.org/homepage/_second_section_text/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eazurich.org/homepage/_second_section_text/</guid>
      <description>We are a welcoming group dedicated to promoting, inspiring and supporting one another to achieve altruistic goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://eazurich.org/homepage/_third_section_text/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eazurich.org/homepage/_third_section_text/</guid>
      <description>Some projects are thousands of times more effective than others. We apply careful reasoning and research to maximise our impact.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>